Erinn Springer

Personal info

First name: Erinn
Last name: Springer

Web: http://www.erinnforzlabels.com
GitHub: https://github.com/elspringer

Address: Silbersteinstraße 147, Berlin 12051, Germany

Phone Number: 3126360793

Email address: erinnlspringer@gmail.com

Profile

I am a fullstack web developer with four years experience building and designing products and five years experience in marketing. With my technical skills, creative chops, experience managing projects and data-driven approach, I'd be a good fit for the Digital Product Manager role at zLabels.

Work experience

Erinn Springer Berlin Germany

Web Designer & Developer

02/2017 - present

Travelogue

- Designed and created the website, travelogue.co.
- Organised and launched events for women only in Berlin.

Teacher & TA at Le Wagon

- · Gave lectures on Rails.
- Helped students with Ruby, Rails, CSS and their final projects that they presented on their demo day.

BlueBuzzard Technology Group Chicago USA

Web Developer

01/2015 - 02/2017

- Learned about the hotel sales and events lifecycles and communication touchpoints to create a roadmap and user stories for building Customer Relationship Management (CRM) software.
- Conceptualized product features with the cofounders of the company, but mostly worked independently.
- Created wireframes and prioritized features.
- Conducted user tests once a new feature was launched to either reiterate, make improvements or move on to the next feature.
- Designed and built CRM software onto existing codebase.
- Built out requests from existing customers and helped move current customers over to the new product features.

GoHealth Chicago USA

Marketing Coordinator

07/2009 - 10/2013

- Created and managed all company email, texting, SEO, social media and public relation campaigns.
- · Worked on user surveys for PR campaigns.
- Wrote press releases and managed relationships with outside public relation agencies. Also worked with internal team to coordinate projects and postings of media coverage.
- Tracked visits in Omniture from SEO keywords, social media and public relations placements to increase future visits.

Education

Starter School Chicago USA

Web Development & Design

10/2013 - 05/2014

Went to a nine-month program that taught design, front-end and back-end development,

Education

user-experience, and business skills.

Specific languages that I learned include: Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, CoffeeScript and more.

Design skills learned include: wireframing, user stories, user testing, copy writing, content management and more.

To read more about the program and my experience at Starter School visit,

http://www.starterschool.com/stories/erinn-barr.

Purdue University West Lafayette USA

JS/JQuery, CoffeeScript

Movement & Sports Science

08/2005 - 05/2009

Obtained a major in Movement & Sport Science at the Liberal Arts School and a minor in Organizational Leadership.

Skills

Development Languages

Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS,

Tools

Google Analytics, Sprout Social, Omniture, Mailchimp, Exact Target, Github

Other Skills

Writing, Content Marketing, Web Analytics, Email Marketing, SEO, Social Media Optimization